<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>YangBin</title>
 <link href="http://yangbin.tk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://yangbin.tk/"/>
 <updated>2012-10-06T01:12:36+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://yangbin.tk/</id>
 <author>
   <name>YangBin</name>
   <email>yangbdy@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>world</title>
   <link href="http://yangbin.tk/2012/10/05/warp.html"/>
   <updated>2012-10-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://yangbin.tk/2012/10/05/warp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id='world'&gt;world&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class='meta'&gt;Oct 05 2012 - Shanghai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;量子力学的多世界解释一直是个充满兴趣的问题。为数不少的物理学家相信多世界解释。今 天高人Raphael Bousso和Leonard Susskind在arXiv上贴了一篇文章：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We argue that the many-worlds of quantum mechanics and the many worlds of the multiverse are the same thing, and that the multiverse is necessary to give exact operational meaning to probabilistic predictions from quantum mechanics. Decoherence - the modern version of wave-function collapse - is subjective in that it depends on the choice of a set of unmonitored degrees of freedom, the &amp;#8220;environment&amp;#8221;. In fact decoherence is absent in the complete description of any region larger than the future light-cone of a measurement event. However, if one restricts to the causal diamond - the largest region that can be causally probed - then the boundary of the diamond acts as a one-way membrane and thus provides a preferred choice of environment. We argue that the global multiverse is a representation of the many-worlds (all possible decoherent causal diamond histories) in a single geometry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We propose that it must be possible in principle to verify quantum-mechanical predictions exactly. This requires not only the existence of exact observables but two additional postulates: a single observer within the universe can access infinitely many identical experiments; and the outcome of each experiment must be completely definite. In causal diamonds with finite surface area, holographic entropy bounds imply that no exact observables exist, and both postulates fail: experiments cannot be repeated infinitely many times; and decoherence is not completely irreversible, so outcomes are not definite. We argue that our postulates can be satisfied in &amp;#8220;hats&amp;#8221; (supersymmetric multiverse regions with vanishing cosmological constant). We propose a complementarity principle that relates the approximate observables associated with finite causal diamonds to exact observables in the hat.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>计算广义相对论的Mathmatica包</title>
   <link href="http://yangbin.tk/2012/10/05/test.html"/>
   <updated>2012-10-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://yangbin.tk/2012/10/05/test</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GR 使用符号计算软件Mathmatica计算广义相对论的包有很多中, 最知名的如&lt;a href='http://grtensor.phy.queensu.ca/'&gt;GRTensor&lt;/a&gt;. 但是我觉得这些包都不是很趁手, 因为就我个人而言, 这些包中很多功能我实际上用不到.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以我自己写了一个只有七个函数的简单包&lt;a href='https://files.dropbox.com/u/36755974/GR.m'&gt;GR&lt;/a&gt;, 可以计算Einstein张量, 克里斯多菲尔记号, 外尔张量等. 您可以随便改动或传播这个包, 不用注明出处. 需要提到的是, 这个包并非完全由我原创, 我是在看了James.Hartle的名著&lt;a href='http://web.physics.ucsb.edu/~hartle'&gt;Gravity: An Introduction to Einstein&amp;#8217;s General Relativity&lt;/a&gt;中附加的代码后, 将其封装成包. 当然如果您觉着好用, 感谢Hartle老先生好了, 譬如买他一本书.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* 使用方法&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;使用说明: 以Vaidya黑洞为例.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ds^{2}=-2f(u,v)dudv+r^{2}(u,v)d^{2}\Omega^{2}$$ 比如计算其Einstein张量:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$Einstein[{0,-f[u,v],0,0},{-f[u,v],0,0,0},{0,0,r[u,v]^2,0},{0,0,0,r[u,v]^2Sin[\theta]^2},{u,v,\theta ,\phi}]$$.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>